[Citizenship](https://corporate.mattel.com/citizenship)﻿

Mattel Privacy Statement
========================

At Mattel, we empower generations to explore the wonder of childhood and reach their full potential.

This Privacy Statement is where we tell you how Mattel, including our affiliates and subsidiaries (including, but not solely, Mattel, Inc., Fisher-Price, Inc., American Girl Brands, LLC, HIT Entertainment Limited, Mega Brands Inc. their affiliate and subsidiaries) (collectively, “Mattel”) handle your personal information and let you tell us what we can do with it. Mattel’s complete list of entities, affiliates, and subsidiaries (“Mattel Group of Companies”) can be found [here](https://shop.mattel.com/mattel-group-of-companies). This Privacy Statement applies to personal data collected and processed by Mattel through our websites, applications, features, or other services that post a link to this Privacy Statement (collectively, the “Services”), as well as personal data collected and held by Mattel offline, which we may combine with online data.

When we talk about “personal information” or “personal data,” we mean information that tells us who you are, where you live, and how we can contact you. We get this information in many ways and from many different places, including from third parties. Some personal information we collect may be considered “sensitive” under various applicable laws. It can be things you give to us directly, like your name, phone number, and email address when you sign up for an account or buy something from us. It can also be things you cannot see that we collect from your computer or mobile phone while you are on our websites, mobile apps, or social media channels. The personal information we collect, such as IP addresses, cookie identifiers, or mobile phone IDs, allow us to send you videos and other content about our toys, movies, and games that we think you may like to see.

In some instances, to comply with good privacy practices and the law, we may de-identify or pseudonymize previously personal information so that it becomes non-personal, such as aggregating and/or or converting it to a code, sometimes using a function commonly known as “hash”, or otherwise removing characteristics that make the data personally identifiable to you. We maintain and use de-identified data without attempting to re-identify it, except where permitted by applicable law, such as to determine whether our de-identification processes satisfy legal requirements. We will treat de-identified or pseudonymized information as non-personal to the fullest extent allowed by applicable law. If we combine non-personal information with personal information, then we will treat the combined information as personal information under this Privacy Statement.

By accessing, using, or otherwise interacting with any part of the Services, or by otherwise providing personal data to Mattel, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Statement and the applicable Terms and Conditions of Use which govern your use of the Services. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Statement and the applicable Terms and Conditions, do not access or use the Services or provide personal data to us.

**Table of Contents**
---------------------

1.     [**Your Privacy Choices**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-your-privacy-choices) 

a. [Opt-Out of Selling/Sharing of Your Personal Information](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-your-privacy-choices1)

b. [Opt-Out of Cookies and Tracking Technologies](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-your-privacy-choices2)

c. [Opt-Out Using Global Privacy Control (“GPC”)](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-your-privacy-choices3)

d. [Opt-Out of Marketing Communications from Us](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-your-privacy-choices4)

2.     [**Personal Information We Collect**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect)

a. [Additional Details about our Data Practices Disclosed in the Table Above](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-additional)

b. [Device ID/Interaction Information](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-device)

c. [Cookies](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-cookies)

d. [Types of Cookies We Use](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-cookie-types)

e. [Interest-Based Advertising/Third-party Advertising & Analytics Companies & Similar Third Parties](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-interest)

f. [Other Websites & Mobile Application Content](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-other)

3.     [**How We Get Your Personal Information**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-how-we-get-your-personal-information)

a. [You Share it Directly](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-how-we-get-your-personal-information)

b. [You Interact with Websites, Mobile Apps & Emails](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-how-we-get-your-personal-information-interact)

c. [We Get it From Other Companies](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-how-we-get-your-personal-information-other)

4.     [**When We Disclose Your Personal Information**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information)

a. [When You Direct Us to Share or Otherwise with Your Consent](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information-direct)

            i. [Social Media and Other Third-Party Platforms](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information-social)

1\. [We Share it With Our Vendors & Service Providers](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information-vendors)

2\. [We Share it for Sweepstakes, Contests, Promotions](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information-sweeps)

3\. [Administrative and Legal Reasons](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information-admin)

4\. [Business Transfers and Transitions](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-when-we-disclose-your-personal-information-business)

5.     [**Children’s Personal Information & Online Safety**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-childrens-personal-information)

6.     [**How We Protect Your Personal Information**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-how-we-protect-your-personal-information)

7.     [**International Transfers**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-international-transfers)

**8.**     [**Regional Disclosures**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures)

a. [U.S. State Privacy Notices](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures)

i. [Notice to California Residents](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-california)

b. [UK and EEA Privacy Notice](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea)

i. [Data Controller information](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-data-controller)

ii. [Mattel EMEA contact information](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-contact)

iii. [How we use your data: purposes and legal basis](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-how-we-use)

iv. [Legitimate interest balancing test](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-legitimate)

v. [Personal information recipients](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-personal-recipients)

vi. [International data transfers](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-international)

vii. [Personal information retention period](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-personal-retention)

viii. [Your rights according to GDPR](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-your-rights) 

c. [Canada Privacy Notice](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-canada)

d. [Australia Privacy Notice](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-australia)

e. [China Privacy Notice](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-china)

f. [Brazil Privacy Notice](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-brazil)

i. [AVISO DE PRIVACIDADE DO BRASIL](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-brazil-aviso)

9.     [**Contact Us**](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-contact-us)

**Your Privacy Choices** 
-------------------------

You have the right to know what personal information we collect about you, how we use it, and to have access to it under privacy laws around the world. You can go to the [Mattel Privacy Choice Portal](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) to learn what may rights may be available to you about these access rights, how and why we use your personal information, to check that we do so lawfully, and gain access for updates, corrections, and deletion. You may have additional specific rights, depending on where you live, please see: Regional Disclosures section, below.

**Opt-Out of Selling/Sharing of Your Personal Information**

You can go to [_Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/1f32dee8-09ca-425b-b9d1-f78a1c2e219e) request that we not share or sell your personal information.

**Opt-Out of Cookies and Tracking Technologies**

Some cookies are required to make our online offerings work, but others are optional. You can go to [_AdChoices_](https://youradchoices.com/)_/_[_the Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) to control what types of cookies we may use when you access Mattel’s websites and other digital apps.

**Opt-Out Using Global Privacy Control (“GPC”)**

You can go to [https://globalprivacycontrol.org/](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) to download the GPC web browser plugin that tells our website your privacy preferences for cookies. We will honor your privacy rights according to the GPC signal you set.

**Opt-Out of Marketing Communications from Us**

We may provide you with the option to update your information or to opt out of marketing communications. You may opt out of marketing communications as set forth below.

1. **Emails.** If you wish to opt out of marketing email messages that we send to you, you can unsubscribe through the opt-out mechanism included in each marketing email we send to you. Note that we reserve the right to send you certain email communications relating to your use of our website, service announcements, notices of changes to this Privacy Statement or our other terms, or similar administrative or transactional messages, and these transactional account messages may be unaffected if you choose to opt-out from e-mail marketing communications.
2. **Text Messages**_._ If you sign up to receive SMS or MMS or RCS messages that may be offered on the Services, you may unsubscribe by replying “STOP.” 
3. **Push Notifications.** If you have accepted push notifications through our mobile application, you can also turn off push notifications in your device settings.

**Personal Information We Collect** 
------------------------------------

The following chart sets out by category the personal data collected, how we use it, and categories of third parties to whom we disclose it for business purposes and, if applicable, to whom it is sold for valuable consideration or shared for cross contextual targeted marketing. 

For more information about certain practices disclosed in the chart, please also see _the_ [_Additional Details About our Data Practices_](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect-additional). These items are indicated with an asterisk (“\*”) and have a numerical tag.

**Category of Personal Information**

**How We Use It & Categories of Use\***

**Categories of Third Parties we Disclose to for Business Purposes or to whom it is Sold/Shared for advertising purposes**

Your contact information, for example:

* Your name.
* Your email address.
* Your phone number.
* Your home address.

* To contact you.
* To send content you ask for.
* To send products you buy from us.
* To send you content we think you will be interested in.
* To sign you up for accounts.
* To sign you up for contests or sweepstakes.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Sweepstakes/contests partners.
* Order fulfillment vendors
* Technology systems.
* Service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Communications services providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers who use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Sold or Shared to Categories of Third parties:

* Third parties in connection with their marketing of similar products related to Mattel products via paper and online catalogues.
* Trusted third-party partners for joint marketing purposes.

Your demographics and interests, for example:

* Your age and gender.
* Your race and ethnic background.
* Your country, town, city, or state.
* How many people live in your house.
* Your salary.
* Whether you are married or single.
* What languages you speak.
* Your education.
* Your job.
* Your purchase history.
* Your hobbies and interests.
* Your personality traits.

* To learn who you are and what you like.
* To learn what products you are likely to buy.
* To send you content we think you will want to see.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Sweepstakes/contests partners.
* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Communications services providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Sold or Shared to Categories of Third Parties:

* Third parties in connection with their marketing of similar products related to Mattel products via paper and online catalogues.
* Trusted third-party partners for joint marketing purposes.

Account Information, for example:

* Mattel IDs for your accounts.
* Your username and passwords.
* Your account settings.

* To sign you on to your accounts.
* To create and maintain your accounts.
* To give you the best shopping experience.
* To remember your personal settings.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Sweepstakes/contests partners.
* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Communications services providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Transaction Information, for example:

* Your purchase history

* To send you account statements.
* Allow you to buy products and services.
* Process and issue refunds and collections.
* Record which products and services you buy.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Sweepstakes/contests partners.
* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Communications services providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Device ID/Interaction Information, for example:

* Internet Protocol (IP) address.
* Media Access Control (MAC) address.
* Service Set Identifier (SSID).
* Mobile device advertising IDs (iOS and Android).
* Other unique identifier.
* Account sign on IDs (username/password).
* Device and browser characteristics.
* How you use and interact with the Services.
* Server, application, and system logs.
* Website and app usage data, including your search terms, pages you visit, content you view and add to your shopping basket, time of your last interaction, time. spent on the Services, and your preferences through a unique visitor ID.

* Make sure our systems continue working properly.
* Learn how to make our websites and apps better.
* Protect your personal information.
* Protect our systems and company information.
* Legal and other compliance requirements.
* To give you the best shopping experience.
* To remember your personal settings.
* To learn who you are and what you like.
* To learn what products you are likely to buy.
* To send you advertisements and other content we think you will want to see.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Sweepstakes/contests partners.
* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Communications services providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely. to provide services to us or to you.

Precise Geolocation, for example:

* Location of your device within three city blocks.
* Location of your device within 1,750 feet of where you are.
* Where you are standing (GPS coordinates).
* Phone signal information (cell-tower triangulation).

* Send marketing messages.
* Send product information.
* Send in-store information.
* To learn who you are and what you like.
* To learn what products you are likely to buy.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Sweepstakes/contests partners.
* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Communications services providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Health-related Information, for example:

* Pregnancy due date
* Disability information via consumer studies.

For information about health-related data processed by Mattel, please read our [_Consumer Health Data Statement_](https://corporate.mattel.com/consumer-health-data).

Payment and Financial Information, for example:

* Bank account number.
* Credit card number.

* Allow you to buy our products.
* Verify parental consent.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors.
* Communications service providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Government-issued IDs, for example:

* Driver’s license.
* Passport.
* Tax ID.

* Verify your identity.
* Verify your child’s age.
* Verify parental consent.
* To provide you services.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third Parties:

* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Sweepstakes/contest partners.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Customer service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Audio Visual Information Photographs, for example:

* Video images.
* CCTV recordings.
* Call center recordings.
* Call monitoring records.
* Voicemails.

* Provide physical security.
* Provide customer service.
* Improve our products/services.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third parties:

* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service providers.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Smart Devices and Sensor Information, for example:

* Smart device records.
* Connected products.
* Device information.

* Send product information.
* Send in-store information.
* To learn who you are and what you like.
* To learn what products you are likely to buy.
* To provide you services.
* To personalize your account.
* For internal business purposes.
* Other purposes as disclosed at the time of collection or with your consent.

Disclosed to Categories of Third parties:

* Advertising and analytics partners.
* Social media platforms.
* Order fulfillment vendors.
* Technology systems service providers.
* Security vendors/service provider.
* Government agencies and law enforcement where required by law.
* Third parties in connection with court or other legal actions.
* Third parties in connection with business transactions.
* Third parties to whom you agree or direct us to share your data.
* Other service providers use your data solely to provide services to us or to you.

Children’s Information, for example:

* Child’s age and gender.

For information about child-related data processed by Mattel, please read our [_Children’s Privacy Statement_](https://corporate.mattel.com/childrens-privacy-statement).

**Additional Details about our Data Practices Disclosed in the Table Above**
----------------------------------------------------------------------------

**How We Use Your Data & Categories of Use.** In the table above, we have provided a list of different types of data (the first column) and associate them with a description of ways we might use that data (the bulleted items in the second column). Some Privacy laws require that we more fully disclose these uses by sorting them into categories. In the chart above, the Category of Use is always associated with a number. This section provides further explanation and information about each Category of Use.

1. **To Provide You the Services**: including to send content you ask for or respond to your support and provide customer service or request feedback from you, to send products you buy from us and otherwise process and fulfill your transactions, to enable you to use the Services and other products and services we offer, including to sign you up for accounts, maintain your account information, and to facilitate your participation in contests or sweepstakes or promotions. 
2. **Advertising Activities and Marketing Messages**: including to customize and optimize content for you, such as recommendations, promotions, and advertisements we display through the Services and elsewhere online; to send you marketing communications if you have provided us your email address, as permitted by applicable law.
3. **Personalization**: including to learn who you are and what you like and what products you are likely to buy, to tailor the content and advertising we display to you or others, on the Services or elsewhere, including content in emails we may send to you, to tell you about new products, promotions, opportunities, or other general information about Mattel or our products that we believe will be of interest to you.
4. **Administrative**: including to verify your identity and age, recognize you across the Services and your devices and remember your preferred settings; contact you regarding your use of the Services, content, features, or products you use or request, and, in our discretion, changes to our policies.
5. **Internal Business Purposes**: including to operate and improve the Services and our products, services, and marketing endeavors; market research; analyze the effectiveness of our marketing efforts; detect and troubleshoot problems; monetize our Services; understand how you use the Services including tracking traffic, usage, trends, and navigation patterns; conduct sales auditing. 
6. **Security**: including to protect integrity of the Services and to investigate issues. 
7. **Legal**: including to comply with the law; resolve disputes; enforce our agreements and policies; cooperate in governmental or other legal inquiries; fulfill regulatory reporting obligations; protect our or others’ rights, assets, safety or security. 
8. **Business Transitions**: including in connection with a merger, acquisition, consolidation, bankruptcy, or other corporate transition, including during due diligence.
9. **Other Purposes as Disclosed at the time of collection/with your consent.**

**Categories of third parties we Disclose to for Business Purposes or to whom it is Sold/Shared for Targeted Advertising**. In the table above, we have provided a list of different types of data (the first column) and associate them with abbreviated categories of certain third parties (the third column). This section provides further examples and extra information about each category of Third-party.

1. **Advertising and Analytics Partners**: including analytics companies, third-party advertisers, marketing agencies. 
2. **Other Mattel Affiliated Companies**: such as, but not limited to, Mattel, Inc., Fisher-Price, Inc., American Girl Brands, LLC, HIT Entertainment Limited, Mega Brands Inc.
3. **Social Media Platforms and Other Third-Party Platforms**:
4. **Sweepstakes/Contest Partners**: including administrators, other prize providers, and prize fulfillment vendors. 
5. **Third-Party Business Partners**: including unaffiliated parties that are joint marketing and licensing partners. 
6. **Order Fulfillment Vendors**: including payment processors, fulfillment centers, delivery services, order tracking vendors.
7. **Technology Systems Service Providers**: including webhosts, database hosts, cloud computing providers, software-as-a-service providers, and technology maintenance and repair vendors.
8. **Security Vendors:** including companies who help secure Mattel systems from unauthorized access or investigate possible security incidents. 
9. **Communications Service Providers**: including email delivery and direct mail vendors, text messaging service providers. 
10. **Customer Service Providers**: including call centers and live chat vendors.

**Device ID/Interaction Information**
-------------------------------------

Mattel and our third-party business partners (including any third-party service providers or third-party content, advertising, and analytics providers) may use a variety of technologies, including cookies and pixel tags, that automatically or passively collect information whenever you access, use, or otherwise interact with the Services (“**Device ID/Interaction Information**”)**.**

**Cookies and Related Technologies**
------------------------------------

A cookie identifies your computer or mobile device. It does not show who you are by name, but does let us know you or someone in your household used the same computer or mobile device that visited a website earlier and can in some situations be connected to a name or a household. It will usually be a file named something like—abc@example.com.txt. If you open one of these files, it will show some random letters and numbers like: “HMP1example.com/04058205\*”.

There are different types of cookies. The most common are session cookies, which are temporary. They are used by nearly all websites to allow things like shopping carts to work, even if you aren't logged in to your account. They simply tell the server that all your requests came from the same computer and should be treated as a single visit to a website. These temporary cookies are deleted when your visit is over, or after a period of no activity (when you make no keystrokes or your mouse stops moving, after about 20 minutes or so).

Permanent cookies, also called persistent cookies, are also common. These cookies are used to identify your computer or mobile device over multiple visits to a website. These are the ones that handle your request to "Remember Me" or "Keep Me Logged In" to a website or app.

These permanent cookies are also used to send you advertisements based on the websites you visit and the content you view during those visits.

They are also used to tell us how long you stay on a site, how you move through the site, and other activities like the content you view or the mouse clicks that you make. They are also used to count the number of visitors to a site, as well as how often returning visitors come back. Website owners use this information to understand how well their websites are doing and to make decisions about how to design the site.

You can choose whether to accept cookies by editing your browser settings. For more information about cookies, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### **Types of Cookies We Use**

For a list of our major technology partners for our Mattel Sites, and the choices and controls they may offer about collection and use of information, read the [THIRD-PARTY TECHNOLOGY LIST](https://assets.contentstack.io/v3/assets/blt485dfa12bf05dba5/bltd15c49511e8547da/6491ae2cf7411bf3f837dbfd/Third_Party_Technology_List_June2023.pdf).

**Required/Strictly Necessary Cookies.** They make our websites work. Without them, you may not be able to view web pages and video content or buy something because the ability to store your information in a shopping cart has been turned off. 

**Functional Cookies.** They make our websites work better. For example, when you choose to read a site in Spanish on your first visit, the next time you come back the site will appear automatically in the Spanish language. Not having to select a language preference every time makes it more user-friendly for you. 

**Analytics Cookies.** They are a type of functional cookie that tells us how well our websites are working. For example, we can learn how many visitors to our websites buy something and how many leave without viewing or clicking on anything. 

**Advertising Cookies.** They tell us what you are interested in based on the websites you visit and the products you buy. That information allows us to send you ads, videos, and other content that better fit the things you like or need. They also allow us to limit the number of times you see the same advertisement.  

### **Other Technologies We May Use**

**Proximity-Based Beacons.** These are small, wireless transmitters that use low energy Bluetooth technology to send signals to other smart devices in their proximity and can be used by mobile applications you have installed on your phone to help locate a device’s location. We may use beacons when your device interacts with the Services, typically through a mobile application, to give you information about products as you walk through a store. Beacons only talk to your device one-way when you get close enough and only after you have given permission in your device settings. 

**Pixels.** These are small graphic images or other web programming code (also known as web beacons or tags) that may be included in our web pages and email messages. These and similar technologies may be used by us and our third-party providers for a number of purposes, including to deliver advertising cookies to your computer or for other marketing and targeted advertising purposes, monitor website activity like counting visitors to the Services, monitor how users navigate the Services, or how many particular products were viewed, make logging into our websites easier, and monitor whether you open our emails or click any links included in our email.

**APIs and SDKs.** We use tools provided in Software Development Kits (“SDKs”), such as embedded scripts, to collect information through mobile devices, such as the hardware model, operating system and version, identification numbers assigned to your mobile device, such as the ID for Advertising (IDFA) on Apple devices, and the Advertising ID on Android devices, mobile network data, and website usage behavior. SDKs are software packages that contain a set of tools that can be used to help build applications and implement new features in existing apps including those that collect data from your device.

In addition, we may use a variety of other technologies that collect similar data for security, fraud detection, and maintenance purposes.

### **Interest-Based Advertising/Third-party Advertising & Analytics Companies & Similar Third Parties**

We may use third-party business partners, such as analytics companies, ad agencies, network advertisers, and others who provide us data about the Services, users, and our advertisements (such as what products and services you’re interested in based on the websites you visit, the content you view online, and the products you buy). These partners deliver ads to you on behalf of the Services and elsewhere online. We and our third-party business partners collect certain data about your visits to and activity on the Services and other websites and services, and may use this data to send you ads for products and services that better fit the things you like or need and to assess the effectiveness of our advertising. We may also share (or permit third parties to collect) certain data, such as Device ID/Interaction Information, aggregated or de-identified, pseudonymized or hashed data (including email addresses), with these third parties for similar purposes.

These third-parties may set and access their own tracking technologies on your device (including cookies, pixel tags or other technologies) and may otherwise collect or have access to your personal data over time, including about your visits to the Services as well as other websites and online services, some of which may be personal information or personal data under various local laws. Companies that we share data with, including ad agencies and networks, may use the data, often in combination with their existing data, in order to present more relevant advertisements that may be of interest to you, and to help us and third parties to do the same.

**Here are some examples of our interest-based advertising practices:**

1. We Learn About People Who Have Similar Interests. We may learn that people who buy children’s clothing also buy toys and games for children within that same age range. Knowing this, we may send ads for toys and games to people who bought children’s clothing because they behave like or “look like” shoppers who tend to also buy toys and games in the same age range.
2. We Combine Information About You from Many Different Sources. We combine information from many different sources, such as how much money you make, your age, gender, and number of people in your family, and the things you buy on and offline. For example, if we know what you have bought from in-store loyalty card swipes, we can send you online information about the things you have already shown interest in offline. In this way, your experience as a consumer is more personal across all your buying channels.
3. We Know You Across All of Your Devices. Linking together your computers, tablets, and phones allows you to log into your account from all your devices or pick up where you left off in a video or movie that you were viewing on a different device. For example, you might search for our entertainment content on your laptop, click on a Google search result link which we have sponsored, and then later be able to purchase that same product after seeing an ad on your mobile phone.
4. We Match You Across all Accounts. We may share your email address with social media companies or use their technology on our websites so that we can communicate with you when you are on social media. We also do this matching to learn if you saw our ad on social media, and if you clicked on it, and then came to our website to buy something. This helps us know if we should continue to buy ads on social media.

**Our Tools.** You can control how your personal information is used for interest-based advertising by visiting [_the Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536). You can also opt out of certain cookies by modifying your [cookie settings](https://consent-pref.trustarc.com/?type=mattel_prod_us_v3&site=mattel.com&country=us&action=prefmgr&locale=en&behavior=implied&gtm=1&autoblock=true&behaviorManager=us&irm=false). You can also go to [https://globalprivacycontrol.org/](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) to download the GPC web browser plugin that tells our website your privacy preferences for cookies. We will honor your privacy rights according to the GPC signal you set. We will honor your privacy rights according to the GPC signal you set.

**NAI/DAA Opt-Out.** Some of the companies we use may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) or Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). The NAI provides information regarding targeted advertising and the [opt-out procedures of NAI members](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/), including opt-out mechanisms for web browsers, mobile and other connected devices, and a tool to opt out from participating NAI members using your hashed email address for interest-based advertising. You may also want to visit the [DAA's website](https://optout.aboutads.info/), which provides information regarding targeted advertising and offers an opt-out for DAA-participating companies. To learn more about interest-based advertisements from participating third parties in Canada, please visit the Canadian DAA online choice page at [https://youradchoices.ca/en/tools](https://youradchoices.ca/en/tools).

**Google Analytics.** We use Google Analytics, which use cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about the use of the Services and report on activities and trends. The Services may also collect information about the use of other websites, apps, and online services. You can [learn about Google's practices](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites), and opt out of them by downloading the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)[.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

Please note that opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising from Mattel. You will continue to see non-targeted advertisements from many companies, possibly even Mattel, while online. In other words, in the case you have expressed your opt-out by the above methods, some online ads will still appear, but these will not benefit from the information Mattel could have otherwise used that is specific to you or your browsing history. The same way a printed newspaper advertisement addresses a large number of readers generally and no one reader in particular, your advertisements after opt-out will be general in nature and are placed by Mattel to advertise to the general public. Your opt-out choices are also browser and device specific; if you disable your cookies or upgrade your browser after opting out, or if you use different computers or browsers, you will need to indicate your opt-out choices across those other computers and browsers.

### **Other Websites & Mobile Application Content**

**Precise Location Data.** We always get your permission before knowing the exact location of your device (also called “precise geolocation”). You may turn off collection of precise location data by adjusting your browser or device settings. Despite this, Mattel may collect and know less specific location information, for example, that your device is anywhere within a broader city, postal code, state or province based on other data we collect, such as IP address, without asking for your permission (called “approximate” or “general location”). For example, we will not seek your permission before knowing you are somewhere in Barcelona, Spain.

**Session Replay Technology.** Mattel may record your interactions with the Services, such as what pages you visit on the Services, how long you visit those pages, and any links you click or information you provide. We use this information for our internal business purposes, such as for website analytics, to improve the Services and our products and services, and to address functionality issues.

**Plugins.** They collect and send information back to the company that created them when you have an account with them and are signed into their services. An example of a plugin is the Facebook “Like” button. Plugins function according to the privacy policies and terms of the company that created them, even though they may appear on our Services.

**Logins.** You may log in to our services using your account with another company such as, for example, “Login with Google.” We have access only to the information you allow us to receive from your account settings with that other company. Like plugins, function according to the privacy policies and terms of the company that created them, even though they may appear on our Services.

**User Content.** We may offer features where you can submit data to us, including to post or submit, without limitation, information, comments, reviews, messages, text, files, photos, videos, or other content you provide (“User Content”). Your Submission of User Content is governed by our [Terms and Conditions](https://corporate.mattel.com/terms-conditions). Anything you post publicly becomes public information and others will have access to it and may use it or share it with third parties. We do not control how others who have access to your information may use your posts, videos, photographs, comments, and other content you create and publicly post and the use of your data by third parties is not subject to this Privacy Statement.

**Third-party Content and Links.** Our Services may include content that is served by someone else or links to third-party content or sites we do not control. The third-party operators and content providers use their own cookies or other tracking technology, and they may independently collect data from or about you. Mattel is not responsible for the privacy policies and terms or practices employed by any third-party.

For a list of our major technology partners for our mobile apps, please see the [MOBILE THIRD-PARTY TECHNOLOGY LIST](https://assets.contentstack.io/v3/assets/blt485dfa12bf05dba5/blt8ae158fc892eb615/672d14cf3bea8f442c121e8e/Mobile_Third_Party_Technology_List_2024.pdf).

**How We Get Your Personal Information**
----------------------------------------

### **You Share it Directly**

You give your personal information to us. It can be things like your name, phone number, and email address when you sign up for an account or buy something from us.

### **You Interact with Websites, Mobile Apps & Emails**

We collect your personal information in ways you cannot see from your computer or mobile phone while you are on our websites, mobile apps, and social media channels. Things like mobile phone IDs allow us to send you videos and other content about our toys, movies, and games that we think you may like to see.

### **We Get it From Other Companies**

We may receive data about you from third parties, such as data aggregators, joint marketing partners, third-party websites, service providers and other business partners. We get data from third parties in order to provide you with information or services you have requested, to tailor content, to offer you opportunities to purchase products or services that we believe may be of interest to you, and for other purposes.

This may include contact information, such as your email or mailing address, so that we may contact you if you express interest in our Services.

You may have given another company permission to share your personal information with us. For example, you may have done this when creating a social media account or joined a loyalty/rewards program with another company. We sometimes buy it from publicly available databases or third parties who enhance the data we have about you. For example, they may sell us information about the number of people in your family and products you have bought on the internet or from stores in your neighborhood.

The data collected and stored by third parties is subject solely to the third-party’s privacy practices. Third parties may also share or sell it without your permission if the law allows them to do so. You can request other companies to stop selling and sharing your personal information by visiting their website and reading their privacy notice.

**When We Disclose Your Personal Information**
----------------------------------------------

We may share non-personal data that we collect, such as certain Device ID/Interaction Information, aggregate user statistics, and hashed or otherwise de-identified or pseudonymized data (including email addresses), and/or our analyses derived from such data, with third-parties in our discretion as permitted by law, including for targeted advertising purposes. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third-party. If you decide that you do not want to receive communications from a third-party, or have questions about their privacy practices, you will need to contact that third-party directly. We may share the data we have collected about you (including personal data) in the circumstances described below or elsewhere in this Privacy Statement, as disclosed at the time you provide data, or otherwise with your consent.

### **When You Direct Us to Share or Otherwise with Your Consent**

We may share your personal information when you expressly consent or otherwise direct us to do so. by law.

### **Social Media and Other Third-Party Platforms**

We may share your personal information with social media companies or use their technology on our websites so that we can send you videos, ads, or other content when you are on social media channels that you signed up for with them. These third-party social media companies may be able to collect certain data about your visits to the Services regardless of whether or not you affirmatively interact with the feature and whether or not you are logged into (or have) an account with the third-party social media company. We work with social media companies to learn if you saw our ad on social media, and if you clicked on it, and then came to our website to buy something. This helps us know if we should continue to buy ads on social media.

If you choose to share content or to otherwise post data through the Services to a third-party social media channel, or vice versa, that data may be publicly displayed. Similarly, as permitted by applicable law, if you post data on a social media channel that references us (for example, by using a hashtag associated with us in your post), your post may be published on the Services or otherwise in accordance with the terms of that third-party. Also, both we and the third-party may have access to certain data about you and your use of the Services and the third-party social media channel. In addition, as you may agree to with a third-party service, we may receive data about you if other users give us access to their profiles and you are one of their “connections” or data about you is otherwise accessible through your profile or similar page. The data collected and stored by the third-party remains subject to the third-party’s privacy practices, including whether the third-party continues to share data with us, the types of data shared, and your choices with regard to what is visible to others on that third-party service. The third party may allow you to remove the application or feature, in which case we will no longer collect information about you through the application or feature, but may retain the information previously collected.

### **We Share it With Our Vendors & Service Providers**

We may share your personal information with other companies who help us run our business. This includes those who run our websites, deliver marketing emails, send ads, help us to understand how our sites and ads are working and what we can do better, and to run credit card payments for us. Our service providers will use your personal information only to help us do these things. Our contracts with them prevent them from selling your personal information to other companies or using it in any other way. Additionally, we may share various information relating to our users and fraudulent or potentially fraudulent activities with our fraud prevention and similar service providers, and they will use this information to help us and their other clients prevent fraudulent and illegal transactions.

### **We Share it for Sweepstakes, Contests, Promotions**

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, or other promotions (any, a "Promotion"), that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to the provisions, conditions, or official rules that govern the Promotion, which may require specific requirements of you (including, without limitation, and except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice, likeness, or other indicia of persona in advertising or marketing materials). If you choose to enter a Promotion, personal data may be disclosed to third-parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s terms or official rules (such as on a winners list).

### **Administrative and Legal Reasons**

Mattel may disclose your personal information in other circumstances as necessary for administrative or legal purposes. For example, we may provide personal information about you to regulatory authorities and law enforcement officials in accordance with applicable law, when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it, or to respond to requests from government authorities. There may be instances when we may use or disclose your personal information in order to protect or defend the legal rights, property or operations of Mattel or our employees or agents; to protect the rights, privacy, safety or security of users, members or others; to protect against fraud; and to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

### **Business Transfers and Transitions**

In the event Mattel goes through a transition (such as a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or sale of all or a portion of its assets, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process), your data (including your personal information) will likely be among the assets transferred. By providing your personal information, you agree that we may transfer such data to the acquiring entity without your further consent, except where required by law.

**Children’s Personal Information & Online Safety**
---------------------------------------------------

Last Updated: May 14, 2024

This Children’s Privacy Statement applies only to the websites or platforms targeted toward users younger than the age of 13 (“**Child”** or “**Children**”) that are owned by Mattel, including our affiliates and subsidiaries (including, without limitation, Mattel, Inc. Fisher-Price, Inc., American Girl Brands, LLC, HIT Entertainment Limited, Mega Brands Inc. and their affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, “**Mattel**”). This Statement provides details regarding data we may collect from Children and supplements our [Privacy Statement](https://corporate.mattel.com/privacy-statement). This Statement applies to personal information collected and processed by Mattel through our websites (the “**Mattel Sites**”), applications, features, or other services that post a link to this Children’s Privacy Statement (collectively, the “**Mattel Services**”).

For information about how Mattel treats data collected from or about users aged 13 and older, please see our [Privacy Statement](https://corporate.mattel.com/privacy-statement), including the specific sections that might apply to where you live. 

### **What Are Mattel’s Children’s Privacy Practices? (Summary)**

Mattel Services which are directed to and accessed by Children call for certain more restrictive privacy practices. Some Mattel Sites or areas of Mattel Sites with content directed toward Children can be identified by “kids” or “play” in the domain or subdomain. Content intended for adults may be available at such Mattel Sites, accessible through a “parents” link.

* We do not collect Personal Information from Children through Mattel Services directed to Children without the consent of a parent or legal guardian, except as permitted by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and other applicable law.
* We may ask a Child for certain information that we do not associate with any Personal Information we have collected about your Child and would not re-display to other users, like their birthdate (if we are restricting certain ages from certain Mattel Services) or to customize their experience by collecting non-identifying information like their gender, their likes and dislikes, and hobbies, etc. This information may be used in aggregated form to help us understand our visitors and improve our products and Mattel services.
* We do not ask for more Personal Information than is necessary for a Child to participate in the activity.
* We take steps to prevent Children from posting or publicly disclosing Personal Information without parental consent, such as monitoring or screening and use of filtering technology.

If you are the parent of guardian of a Child who uses the Mattel Services and have questions, you may contact us using the information in the “[Contact Us](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-contact-us)” information referenced at the bottom of our [Privacy Statement](https://corporate.mattel.com/privacy-statement).

### **What Information Does Mattel Collect from Children and How Is It Used?**

Mattel might collect an email address and first name (or screen name) from your Child without your consent, but only in the following special cases:

* To participate in special activities, like scavenger hunts, personalized pages, games or clubs, we might ask your Child to register. They can often do so anonymously by just providing a first name or username, and password. When we ask for your Child’s first name, we encourage them to use a “screen name” (not their real name) that only they know. Sometimes we will ask your Child to make up a special password so that only they can see their customized areas of Mattel Services. As COPPA requires, we will get your permission should we ask your child to provide additional Personal Information to participate in such activities.
* We may sometimes need a Child’s email address, your email address, or both. We may ask a Child for your email address, so we can notify you of your Child’s interest in Mattel Services. In the limited circumstances where we might collect your Child’s email address without getting your consent first, we ask your Child for your email or mailing address so that we can notify you of your Child’s request and get your permission or give you an opportunity to opt-out. When we ask for your permission, we will tell you what we will do with the information you or your Child provides us, and how you can review your Child’s information and ask us to delete the information. With your consent, we may collect other Personal Information from your Child such as a last name or home address, if the information is necessary for a particular activity. We provide further detail about the instances in which we may request such consent from you below.
* If a Child sends a request to us, we keep their email address for long enough to respond to them. Mattel deletes this information from our system after we answer their question. In the case of “send a friend” emails, we do not ask for your Child’s email address and only use the friends’ email address to send the message, after which the friends’ email addresses are deleted.
* If a Child signs up for an email newsletter or other activity that requires multiple online contacts with the Child, we also ask the Child for a parent’s or legal guardian’s email address, so we can notify you and give you an opportunity to opt out.
* Occasionally, Mattel has special activities or promotions, like sweepstakes or contests that are open to Children. We ask your Child to give us your email address, so that we can tell you that they have registered in a promotion or for a service. If we need more than an email address and first name (or screen name) to enter your Child in the promotion, award a prize, or offer the service, we will notify you, explain what information we need and why, and generally ask that you (not your Child) provide it. For instance, we might ask you for your mailing address so that we can send any prizes your Child wins to you, or for your phone number so that we can contact you if your Child has won. Any information we receive from you or your Child in the above special circumstances will be deleted from our database once the promotion, program or activity is concluded, and after any legally required period for keeping such information is complete.
* As otherwise permitted by COPPA.

Mattel may collect and store other Personal Information about Children if it is submitted by a Child with prior parental consent. Specifically, Mattel may collect Personal Information about a Child in the following instances:

* We may offer enhanced Mattel Services, including subscription-based Mattel Services, which require a parent to register and establish the appropriate permission level for the Child. Content and activities available may vary depending on the Service. Parents will be provided with information on the type of content and activities their Child may access at the time they register and are always responsible for and in charge of their Child’s account. Subscription fees may apply for some Services.
* We do not keep your (or your Child’s) email address unless you tell us it is okay. If social networking opportunities are available through Mattel Services, they are structured so that no Personal Information is shared between visitors unless parental consent is obtained. Similarly, no Personal Information is collected from Children to participate in these features except as described in this section, with parental consent, or as otherwise permitted under COPPA.

### **Automatically Collected Information**

We use persistent identifiers, such as tracking technology, like cookies, for internal operations such as to recognize visitors by their username when they use or revisit Mattel Services, to screen for age, and to provide us important information that helps us understand features and gauge interest. We may also use technology for similar purposes in our apps.

We also use such technology and work with third-party technology partners to facilitate the ability to play games, to recognize returning visitors, for research, and for other purposes, including to screen under-age visitors from certain features or areas intended for older visitors, and for other internal purposes. You may review additional information about these technologies in the section below.

The technologies that may be used to collect information include:

* **Cookies**. A cookie is a data file placed on your computer or other device when you visit the Mattel Services or otherwise access our online content. Cookies may be used for many purposes, such as supporting functionality, for internal analytics and similar internal purposes.
* **Pixel Tags.** We or our third-party service providers (such content providers and analytics companies) may set pixel tags (small graphic images or other web programming code, also known as “web beacons” or "1x1 GIFs" or "clear GIFs") and similar technologies on the Mattel Services. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on your computer such as cookies, the time and date a page is viewed, and a description of the page where the web beacon is placed. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Mattel Services, to monitor how users navigate the sites, and to improve your experience.
* **Embedded Scripts.** An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your device from our web server or a third-party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Mattel Services, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

### **Disclosure of Children’s Personal Information**

Mattel may disclose Children's Personal Information to service providers who provide support for the internal operations of the Mattel Services and who do not disclose or use the Personal Information for any other purpose. These service providers may provide support services such as hosting the Mattel Services, designing and/or operating the features, or performing other administrative services. Mattel may provide these companies with access to Children's Personal Information in order for them to carry out the services they are performing on Mattel’s behalf. These service providers have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of this Personal Information they obtain from Mattel.

We may also disclose Personal Information to third parties when necessary to protect the security or integrity of the Mattel Service; take precautions against liability; respond to judicial process; or provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation on a matter related to public safety.

### **Third-party Links/Can My Child Access the Web Through Mattel Services?**

Your Child can navigate to the general internet through links to third-party web sites available on the Mattel Services that Mattel does not control. Mattel is not responsible for the privacy or data collection practices of any third-party. Third-party websites, online services, or apps that can be accessed through a Mattel Service are governed by the third-party’s privacy practices, and not this Privacy Statement. We recommend that you check the applicable privacy statement and terms of use each time you use any website, online service, or app so you understand how your and your Children’s Personal Information will be collected and used, and by whom.

We encourage you to spend time with your Children when they are online or using any mobile device or connected product so you understand the features of the Mattel Services and the activities they allow, and to adopt available device and browser controls that reflect your preferences about your Children’s ability to access the internet or make purchases online.

### **Can I Access, Update, and Review Information You Have About My Child?**

If you no longer want your Child to participate in an email newsletter, simply click on the link that is provided to unsubscribe, which is usually located at the bottom of the email, or contact us at [service@mattel.com](mailto:service@mattel.com) for Mattel, Fisher-Price, HIT Entertainment, and MEGA Brands; or [service@americangirl.com](mailto:service@americangirl.com) for American Girl.

You may also request to review and delete all Personal Information Mattel has collected about your Child and cease all further collection or use of such Personal Information by submitting a request for Access or Deletion using [_the Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536).

### **A special note to Children**

Children should get a parent’s or legal guardian’s permission before giving out personal contact information or any other Personal Information, to Mattel or to anyone else.

### **Changes to this Statement**

Mattel may update this Children’s Privacy Statement at any time and any changes will be effective upon posting. Where required by COPPA, we will obtain additional parental consent prior to using or disclosing Personal Information in a manner materially different from the purpose for which it was collected.

**How We Protect Your Personal Information**
--------------------------------------------

We use commercially reasonable privacy and cybersecurity protections including technical, organizational, and physical measures. Despite this, no data transmission over the Internet, wireless transmission, or electronic storage of data can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Mattel cannot ensure or warrant the security of any data we collect. You use the Services and provide us with your data at your own risk.

**International Transfers**
---------------------------

Mattel is a US-based company. Your personal information may be stored in other countries. For example, if you live in Europe, we may store it on a server in the United States. By accessing using the Services, or providing us with any data, you fully understand and unambiguously consent to this transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing, and storage of your data in the United States and other jurisdictions, for which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside and/or are a citizen. As a result, this data may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States and other countries according to the laws in those jurisdictions. Please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) to learn about how you can control our use of your personal information.

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**
-------------------------------------

﻿To the extent allowed by applicable law, we reserve the right to change or modify this Privacy Statement in our discretion at any time. Mattel will notify you of material changes by posting the changed or modified Privacy Statement on our Services. We may also provide notice to you in other ways in our discretion, such as through contact information you have provided. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Statement unless otherwise specified. We will provide notice and obtain your consent to the updated privacy statement, which may be opt-in or opt-out consent, if required, or which may occur through your continued use of the Services to the fullest extent allowed by applicable law.

**Contact Us**
--------------

If you have any questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Statement, or our treatment of your personal data, you may contact [Mattel Global Consumer Support](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case). Please indicate which of our brands you have interacted with in the subject line.

**Regional Disclosures**
------------------------

### **U.S. State Privacy Notices**

U.S. state privacy laws require we tell you about what personal information we collect, if we share it, and your rights to access it and request, deletion, correction, and a copy of it. States with these types of laws include California, Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Texas, Utah, Virginia, and Oregon (collectively, the “U.S. Privacy Laws”).

* **Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas, Utah, and Virginia.** We set forth above the categories of personal data we process, the purpose for processing personal data, the categories of personal data shared, and the categories of third parties with whom personal data is shared. Residents of these states have certain privacy rights with respect to this data, as described below. If you are a Consumer residing in one these states (as defined in each state’s respective law) and would like to exercise your applicable rights, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) or call 1-800-524-8697 to submit a request.

**Access Your Personal Information/Data Portability.** To confirm whether we are processing your personal data and request to access such data, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536). This includes to obtain a copy of the personal data previously provided by you to us and, to the extent feasible, in a readily usable format to allow data portability.

**Delete Your Personal Information.** To request to delete your personal data, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536).

**Correct Your Personal Information.** To correct the personal data we hold about you, please go to [_the Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536).

**Opt-Out of Targeted Advertising.** Mattel engages in online advertising practices (and certain analytics or similar activities) that may be considered “targeted advertising” under these states’ laws. To disable sharing through cookies set by third parties that may be considered targeted advertising under such laws, Mattel uses the cookie manager to permit you to adjust your [cookie settings](https://consent-pref.trustarc.com/?type=mattel_prod_us_v3&site=mattel.com&country=us&action=prefmgr&locale=en&behavior=implied&gtm=1&autoblock=true&behaviorManager=us&irm=false). Please also review the _Third-Party Advertising and Analytics_ section above for information on industry tools and device settings that may be available to you. section above for information on industry tools and device settings that may be available to you.

**Opt-Out of Sales of Your Personal Data.** Mattel may sell your data as defined by certain state laws. To opt-out of the sales of your personal data, please go to [Do Not Sell/Share My Data](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/1f32dee8-09ca-425b-b9d1-f78a1c2e219e).

**Right to Appeal.** If, for any reason, you would like to appeal our decision relating to your request and your state provides you with such a right, you have the right to submit an appeal and can do so by going to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) or calling 1-800-524-8697. Please include your full name, the basis for your appeal, and any additional information to consider.

**Sensitive Data.** Where required by law, we will obtain your consent to the processing of any Sensitive Data (as defined by the applicable state law) we collect and otherwise will notify you at or before the time of collection of Sensitive Data. If you wish to opt out of our processing of your Sensitive Data, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536).

* **Nevada.** If you are a Nevada resident, please note that we do not sell your personal data (or “covered information”) as defined in Nevada S.B. 220.

### **Notice to California Residents**

* **California Privacy Notice.** This notice supplements the information contained in Mattel’s Global Privacy Statement and applies only to California residents. This California Privacy Notice sets forth the disclosures and rights for California Consumers regarding their Personal Information, as required by the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 ("CCPA"), the California Privacy Rights Act of 2020 ("CPRA"), and any implementing regulations adopted thereunder. Terms (including defined capitalized terms) used in this California Privacy Notice have the same meanings given in the CCPA, CPRA, and the associated regulations, unless otherwise defined.

**Exercising Your California Rights**

California Consumers have the right to request: (1) that we disclose to you what personal information we collect, use, disclose, and sell/share, including the right to request that we provide to you the specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you (“**Right to Know**”); (2) that we delete the personal information we have collected from you (“**Right to Delete**”); and, (3) that we correct inaccurate personal information we hold about you (**“Right to Correct**”); (4) to opt out from the sharing of your personal information and sensitive personal information to a third-party for cross-context behavioral advertising (i.e. targeted advertising) (“**Right to Opt-Out of Sharing**”); (5) to opt-out from the sale of personal information and sensitive personal information (“**Right to Opt-Out of Sale**”); and (6) that we limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information to purposes set forth in the statute, including that use which is necessary and anticipated to perform the services or provide the goods reasonably expected by an average consumer who requests those goods or services (“**Right to Limit the Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information**”), all subject to the meanings and exceptions set forth in the CCPA and CPRA. More information on each of these rights is below.

In your request, you must provide enough information to allow us to verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information, or their authorized representative. You must also describe your request with enough detail so that we can understand, evaluate, and respond to it. We cannot respond to your request if we cannot verify your identity. Making such a request does not require you to create an account with us, and we will only use the information you provide in a request to verify your identity.

**Verifying Your Requests**

We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity based upon the information you provide and the type of request you are making.

When you exercise your Right to Know, Right to Delete, and/or Right to Correct Inaccurate Information, we may ask that you provide us with information, beyond your full name, in order to verify your identity and fulfill your request. If we are unable to verify that the individual submitting the request is the same individual about whom we have collected information (or someone authorized by that individual to act on their behalf), we will not be able to process the request.

**Agents**

If you are an authorized representative submitting a request on a user's behalf, please complete the applicable request per the instructions below. We will follow up to request a signed, written permission signed by the individual who is the subject of the request authorizing you to make the request on their behalf. The written permission must state your full legal name, the full legal name of the individual who is the subject of the request, and needs to be clear about the permission granted. Alternatively, you may submit a copy of a power of attorney under Probate Code sections 4000-4465. In either case, please also indicate in your email the nature of your request. The consumer's identity, in addition to your own, will need to be independently verified in order for us to be able to fulfill your request. We may also ask the consumer to directly confirm with us that they provided you permission to submit a request. Please keep in mind that if we do not receive adequate proof that you are authorized to act on the consumer's behalf, we may deny the request.

**Right to Know**

California Consumers have the right to know what information we have collected about you (the categories and the specific pieces of information). If you are a California consumer and would like to exercise your Right to Know, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) or 1-800-524-8697.

**Right to Delete**

California Consumers have the right to request that we delete information we have collected from you. If you are a California consumer and would like to exercise your Right to Delete, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) or 1-800-524-8697.

**Right to Correct Inaccurate Information**

California Consumers have the right to request that we correct inaccurate information we hold about you. If you are a California consumer and would like to exercise your Right to Correct, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) or 1-800-524-8697.

**Right to Limit the Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information**

Under the CPRA, a business must only provide the Right to Limit the Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information when such Sensitive Personal Information is collected or processed for the purpose of inferring characteristics about a consumer, or does not fall under certain statutory exceptions, pursuant to CPRA §1798.121. Mattel does not use Sensitive Personal Information for such purpose and/or its use or disclosure falls within the statutory exceptions. Therefore, the Right to Limit the Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information is not triggered under the law at this time.

**Right to Opt-Out of the Sale of Personal Information or Sharing for Cross Contextual Behavioral Advertising**

California consumers have the right to opt-out of the “sale” of your personal information or sensitive personal information or “sharing” for cross contextual behavioral advertising. Mattel does not sell your personal information for monetary compensation, but as discussed above, Mattel engages in certain online advertising practices (and third-party analytics and similar activities), which may be considered a “sale” or “share” for cross-context behavioral advertising (i.e., targeted advertising), whether or not for monetary or other valuable consideration.

If you are a California consumer and would like to exercise your Right to Opt-Out of “Sale” or “Sharing”, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536) or 1-800-524-8697.

To disable sharing through cookies set by third parties that may be considered "sales" or "sharing" under the CCPA and CPRA, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536). In addition, the Digital Advertising Alliance also offers tools for California consumers to send requests under the CCPA and CPRA to opt out of the sale of personal information by some or all of the participating companies [https://www.privacyrights.info/](https://www.privacyrights.info/).

**Data Retention**

We will retain all categories of personal information described in this California Privacy Notice for as long as it is reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this California Privacy Notice, considering the time period reasonably necessary to: use the Services; exercise the choices and rights you have requested; comply with our contractual obligations; enforce our terms for use of the Services; and comply with legal and regulatory requirements. Except as noted differently on specific pages or apps, we retain your personal information while you have an account with us, or while you are using our or continuing to visit us.

**Users Younger than Age 16**

Mattel does not knowingly sell or share Personal Information of users younger than 16 years of age.

**Right to Non-Discrimination for the Exercise of a Consumer's Privacy Rights**

California consumers have the right to not receive discriminatory treatment for exercising CCPA and CPRA rights. We will not discriminate against you for exercising your CCPA and CPRA rights.

**Do Not Track**

Do Not Track (“DNT”) signals offered by some web browsers are settings that request that a web application disable its tracking of an individual user. When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, analytics companies, ad networks, plug in providers, and/or other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity. To learn more about DNT, please go to [https://globalprivacycontrol.org](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/) to download the GPC web browser plugin that tells our website your privacy preferences for cookies. We will honor your privacy rights according to the GPC signal you set.

**Notice of Financial Incentive**

Under California regulations, certain programs we offer that provide benefits to consumers may be considered financial incentive programs. We may collect personal information from you in connection with these programs, e.g., such as contact information (name, email address, phone number) and certain commercial information (e.g., purchase history) for a number of reasons, including to administer the program, contact you with regard to your account (if any), to provide the benefits to you, to better serve you, and to fulfill your requests associated with the program.

To opt into the programs, you may need to provide certain information, register for an account and agree to the applicable program terms, or otherwise follow the instructions associated with that applicable program. Please also see the terms of the program you are joining for additional description of the program and any additional requirements. Participation in our loyalty or other similar programs is voluntary and you can withdraw at any time. To withdraw from loyalty or other programs, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536).

To the extent that we provide a program that may be considered a financial incentive because the program is directly or reasonably related the collection, deletion or sale or retention of consumer personal information, the value is reasonably related to the overall value we receive from the personal information participants provide specific to the program minus the costs and expenses we incur in providing the program.

**Personal Information We Collect**

The personal information we collect about you will depend upon how you use the Services or otherwise interact with us. Accordingly, we may not collect all of the below information about you.

In addition to the below, we may collect and/or use additional types of information, and will do so after providing notice to you and obtaining your consent to the extent such notice and consent is required by the CCPA and CPRA.

**Categories of Personal Information and Sources from which the Information was Collected**

**Business or Commercial Purpose(s) for which Information is Collected**﻿

**Categories of third parties to whom this type of Personal Information is Disclosed for a Business Purpose or Sold/Shared for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising**

Contact Information:

* Your name.
* Your email address.
* Your phone number.
* Your home address.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* Retail partners who send you catalogues.

Demographics and Interests.

* Your age, gender, and birthdate.
* Your race and ethnic background.
* Your country, town, city, or state.
* How many live in your house.
* Your salary.
* Whether you are married or single.
* What languages you speak.
* Your education.
* Your job.
* Your purchase history.
* Your hobbies and interests.
* Your personality traits.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* None.

Account Information

* Your Contact Information.
* Your Demographics and Interests.
* Your Commercial Information.
* Mattel IDs for your accounts.
* Your username and passwords.
* Your account settings.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* None.

Commercial Information

* Your Contact Information.
* Your Account Information.
* Your Demographics and Interests.
* Your Financial Information.
* Your purchase history.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who process payments.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* None.

Online and Technical Information

* Internet or other electronic network activity information.
* Internet Protocol (IP) address.
* Media Access Control (MAC) address.
* Service Set Identifier (SSID).
* Mobile advertising IDs (Android and iOS).
* Account sign on IDs (username/password).
* Device and browser characteristics.
* Server, application, and system logs.
* Website and app usage data.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* None.

General location Information

* General device location in a city or state.
* Where device accesses internet (MAC address).
* Internet address for your device (IP address).

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* None.

Government-issued IDs

* Driver’s license.
* Passport.
* Tax ID.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who process payments.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for cross-contextual behavioral advertising:

* None.

Audio, Electronic, Visual, or Similar Information

* Photographs.
* Video images.
* CCTV recordings.
* Call center recordings.
* Call monitoring records.
* Voicemails.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who help with customer service.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for Cross-Contextual Behavioral Advertising:

* None.

Connected Devices and Sensor Information

* Connected device sensor information.
* Mobile app personalized settings.

* Connected device sensor information.
* Mobile app personalized settings.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for cross-contextual behavioral advertising:

* None.

**Categories of Sensitive Personal Information**

Precise location

* Precise device location within three city blocks.
* Precise device location within 1,750 feet of where you are standing.
* Exactly where you are standing (GPS coordinates).
* Phone signal information (cell-tower).

* Precise device location within three city blocks.
* Precise device location within 1,750 feet of where you are standing.
* Exactly where you are standing (GPS coordinates).
* Phone signal information (cell-tower).

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who verify identity and age.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for cross-contextual behavioral advertising:

* None.

Racial or Ethnicity

Your Demographics and Interests.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who verify identity and age.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for third-party commercial purposes:

* None.

Biometric Information

* Facial recognition.
* Fingerprints.
* Retinal scans.

* Facial recognition.
* Fingerprints.
* Retinal scans.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who verify identity and age
* Mattel affiliates and related entities

Sale/Sharing for cross-contextual behavioral advertising:

* None

Health-related Information

* Pregnancy due date.
* Disability information via consumer studies for product development.

* Pregnancy due date.
* Disability information via consumer studies for product development.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who verify identity and age.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for cross-contextual behavioral advertising:

* None.

Financial Information

* Banking information.
* Credit card information.

* Banking information.
* Credit card information.

Sharing for Mattel business purposes:

* Service providers who help us run our business.
* Service providers who help with marketing efforts.
* Service providers who verify identity and age.
* Mattel affiliates and related entities.

Sale/Sharing for cross-contextual behavioral advertising:

* None.

* **Shine the Light / Your California Privacy Rights.** Mattel does not share personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes (as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83) unless we give you choice (to opt in or opt-out) before sharing with those third parties.

If you are a California consumer and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please go to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536). You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” or contact us via this [form](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case). You must include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

### **UK and EEA Privacy Notice**

If you are a resident of the United Kingdom (UK), European Economic Area (EEA), or of Switzerland, the following information applies.

**Data Controller information**

A data controller means the subsidiary or affiliated entity of The Mattel Group of Companies that is responsible for the personal information collected and used within the scope of this Statement from our sites and applications. To this end, we inform you that the Mattel companies mentioned in this section have entered into the relevant joint controllership agreement. If you would like more information on this matter, you can request it at the contact addresses provided in the Section [_Mattel EMEA Contact Information_](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-contact).

If you live in the UK, Europe, Middle East, or Africa, your personal data shall be jointly controlled by the following Mattel companies:

* Mattel Europa B.V., Gondel 1, 1186 MJ Amstelveen, The Netherlands
* MATTEL Gesellshchaft .m.b.H., Hauptstraßsse 82, A-2384 Breitenfurt near Vienna, Austria 
* Mattel NV/SA Belgium NV, Spaces De Kleetlaan 4, 1831 Machelen, Belgium 
* Mattel Czech Republic s.r.o., The Forum, Václavské nám. 19, 110 00, Prague 1, Czech Republic Vaclavske namesti 832/19, Nove Mesto, 110 00, Parah 1 
* Mattel Northern Europe A/S, Langebrogade 5, 1411 Copenhagen, Denmark Kampmannsgade 2, 1604 Copenhagen V, Denmark 
* Mattel France S.A., 3 allée des Fleurs, Parc de la Cerisaie, 94260 Fresnes, France
* Mattel GmbH, Solmstrasse 4 83, D-60486 Frankfurt, Germany Solmsstrasse 83, 60486, Frankfurt a.M., Germany 
* Mattel AEBE, 1, Ethnarchou Makariou Street, 175 61 Palaio Faliro, Greece
* Mattel Toys Hungary KFT., 2161 Csomád, Levente utca 14a. ep
* Mattel Italy s.r.l., Via Filippo Turati, 4, Italia 20122 Milano (MI) Italy
* Mattel Poland Sp. z o.o., Prosta Str 67, PL-00-838 Warsaw, Poland
* Mattel Portugal Lda, Rua Carlos Alberto da Mota Pinto, nº 17 3A 1070-313 Lisboa, Portugal Rue Luciana Stegagno Picchio, nº 3 -1º, Esq., 1500-912 Lisbon, Portugal 
* Mattel España S.A., Aribau, 200-210, 08036 Barcelona, Spain
* Mattel UK Ltd, 3rd Floor The Porter Building, 1 Brunel Way, Slough, SL1 1FQ United Kingdom

If you live in the US, Canada and other regions:

* Mattel, Inc., 333 Continental Boulevard, El Segundo, California 90245-5012
* Fisher-Price, Inc., 636 Girard Ave, East Aurora, NY 14052
* American Girl Brands, LLC, 333 Continental Boulevard, El Segundo, California 90245-5012
* HIT Entertainment Limited, The Porter Building, 3rd Floor, 1 Brunel Way, Slough, SL1 1FQ United Kingdom
* Mega Brands ULC, 6767 Chemin de la Côte-de-Liesse, Montréal, Québec, H4T 1E5, Canada
* Mattel do Brasil, Rua Verbo Divino, 1488 - 2º andar, CEP: 04719-904, Chácara Santo Antônio, São Paulo/SP

### **Mattel EMEA contact information**

If you have any questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Statement, or our processing of your personal data, you may contact us via this [form](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case). Please indicate which of our brands you have interacted with in the subject line.

### **How we use your data: purposes and legal basis**

Regarding the Section [_Information We Collect_](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-personal-information-we-collect)_,_ we are required to inform you what legal basis we are considering for carrying out the relevant processing activity. To this extent, here you have a new chart where you can notice them:

**Purpose**

**Legal Basis**

**Type of Personal Information**

To provide you the services.

Performance of a contract.

* Contact information.
* Account information.
* Transaction information.
* Payment and Financial information.
* Smart Devices and Sensor Information.

Personalization.

Consent.

* Device ID/Interaction Information.
* Your demographics and interests.
* Account Information.
* Children’s Information.
* Smart Devices and Sensor Information.

Advertising Activities and Marketing Messages.

Legitimate interest and/or your consent.

* Device ID/Interaction Information.
* Your demographics and interests.
* Transaction information.
* Health-related information.
* Children’s Information.

Administrative.

Performance of a contract and/or legitimate interest.

* Account Information.
* Device ID/Interaction Information.

Internal Business Purposes and Security.

Legitimate interest.

* Device ID/Interaction Information.
* Transaction information.

Legal.

Fulfillment of legal obligations.

* Device ID/Interaction Information.
* Transaction information.

Regarding the processing activities called “Personalization,” it is our duty to inform you that we gather the applicable personal information in order to create a profile, which allows us to send you offers of your interest or help you through your purchase process. However, please note that this processing activity is always carried out based on your consent. If you would like to be provided with more information regarding this processing activity, please refer to the relevant addresses set forth within Section Mattel EMEA Contact Information. You can withdraw your consent at any time as set forth in Section [_Your rights according to GDPR_](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-your-rights).

### **Legitimate interest balancing test**

When we rely on legitimate interests, we are taking on extra responsibility for considering and protecting individual’s rights and interests. We rely on legitimate interest as a legal basis where we use your data in ways you would reasonably expect and which have a minimal privacy impact, or where there is a compelling justification for the processing. You can object to us doing so at any time.

We want to let you know that we have conducted balance tests to determine if we can process your personal data based on our legitimate interests. These tests analyze the potential impact on your rights and freedoms from our processing activities. Our findings are that the processing activities are proportionate and pose no harm to you. Our aim is to help you make informed purchasing decisions.

### **Personal information recipients**

**Other companies from the Mattel group.** With your consent, we may share your personal information with other companies within our group, so that they can send you promotional updates or product information. Please, note that certain entities are located outside the EEA. We will only transfer your personal information in accordance with adequate safeguards according to GDPR standards.

**Public authorities and agencies.** On some occasions, the applicable regulations require sharing information with public authorities or agencies so that they can carry out their functions. For example, tax authorities or courts of law, which would use your personal information for their own purposes.

**Service providers.** We make sure that all our service providers act in a confidential manner and in compliance with GDPR and applicable regulations on data protection. Our service providers never use your personal information for their own purposes, but simply to help us provide our services to you. Some of these service providers are located in or may access personal information from outside the EEA, so we have adopted appropriate safeguards to ensure that the personal data is treated with a level of protection equivalent to that which exists in the EEA.

**International data transfers**

**Transfers.** We operate globally and may transfer your personal information to individual companies of The Mattel Group of Companies or third parties in locations around the world for the purposes described in this privacy notice. Wherever your personal information is transferred, stored or processed by us, we will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. These steps may include implementing standard contractual clauses where recognized by law, obtaining your consent, or other lawful means of transferring personal information. If you wish to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses, please refer to the relevant addresses set forth within Section [Mattel EMEA Contact Information](https://shop.mattel.com/privacy-statement#anchor-regional-disclosures-uk-eea-contact).

### **Personal information retention period**

The personal information processed will be kept for as long as the purpose for which they were collected is maintained.

However, when we request your consent or you have the possibility to object the processing activity, we will stop processing the personal information as soon as You withdraw your consent, or you object the processing activity.

That is to say, if you revoke your consent or exercise your objection right, your personal data will be kept during the legally established periods in order to attend to possible liabilities arising from the processing activities thereof. To this extent, your personal information shall be kept for the formulation, exercise or defense of potential claims, only if it allowed by the applicable legislation, or to make the personal information available to judges and courts or competent public authorities. At the end of this extra period, we undertake to cease processing all your personal data.

### **Your rights according to GDPR**

GDPR and other applicable legislation acknowledge the following rights for data subjects like you. To this extent, you may exercise these rights by going to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536). Your privacy rights are the following:

**Right to lodge a complaint.** Users that reside in the UK, EEA, or Switzerland have the right to seek information and assistance or lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority where they reside.

Contact details for data protection authorities are available below:

* **UK:** [https://ico.org.uk/](https://ico.org.uk/)
* **EEA:** [https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members\_en](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en)
* **Switzerland:** [https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/links/data-protection---switzerland.html](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/links/data-protection---switzerland.html)

**Withdraw consent.** If we have collected personal information with your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.

**Access.** You have the right to request access to personal information we collected about you and information about its sources, purposes, and sharing.

**Correction.** You have the right to request that we correct the personal information we hold about you if it is inaccurate or incomplete.

**Erasure.** You have the right to request that we erase data we have collected from you. Please note that we may have a reason to deny your deletion request or delete data in a more limited way than you anticipated, e.g., because of a legal obligation to retain it.

**Portability.** You have the right, in certain circumstances, to request that we provide your personal information to you in a format that can be transferred to another entity.

**Restrict Processing.** You have the right, in certain circumstances, to request that we limit our processing of your personal information if you are (1) contesting the accuracy of your personal information; (2) asserting that our processing is unlawful; and (3) asserting that we no longer need to keep the information for reasons related to the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims, or you object to our processing. You have the right, in certain circumstances, to request that we limit our processing of your personal information if you are contesting the accuracy of your personal information; asserting that our processing is unlawful; asserting that we no longer need to keep the information for reasons related to the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims, or you object to our processing.

**Object.** You have the right to object to our processing if we are processing your personal information based on legitimate interests, using your personal information for direct marketing (including profiling), or processing your personal information for purposes of scientific or historical research and statistics.

**Right not to be subject to automated-decision making.** Individuals have the right to not to be subject to a decision when it is based on automated processing; and it produces an adverse legal effect or significantly affects the individual.

**Verification Procedures_._** We may ask you to verify your identity for everyone’s protection, so we may require you to provide us with verification information prior to accessing any records containing personal information about you. We do this by asking you to provide personal identifiers we can match against information we may have collected from you previously and confirm your request using the email or telephone account stated in the request.

We will use the information you provide for verification only for the purpose of verification. We may have a reason under the law why we do not have to respond to your request or respond to it in a more limited way than you anticipated. If we do, we will explain that to you in our response.

﻿### ﻿**Canada Privacy Notice**

**_Quebec residents - please also see the Notice to Quebec Residents below._**

You may withdraw consent at any time (subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice). Subject to certain limits set out in the applicable laws, Canadian residents also have the right to request access to the personal information that Mattel collects and to update or correct personal information if it is inaccurate. We may need to verify your identity before implementing your request.

Subject to applicable law, if you are a Canadian resident and would like to submit a request to access, correct, or update your personal information, or to withdraw consent to the processing of your personal data, you must submit your request via our [form](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case) or call 1-800-524-8697.  You may also use this contact to submit any requests for information on our privacy practices or to submit a complaint regarding our practices.

Your request or complaint must include your full name, street address, city, province, postal code, and an email address so that we are able to contact you if needed regarding this request.

We cannot properly process requests or complaints that do not come through the designated request mechanism or do not contain sufficient information to allow us to process your request. You may also be required to take reasonable steps as we determine from time to time in order to verify your identity and/or the authenticity of the request. Once your request is processed, absent exemptions, we will provide you with details regarding what personal information we have, how it is used, and with which third-parties it is shared.

* **Notice to Quebec Residents.**

All Mattel personnel handling personal information will be subject to a duty of confidentiality and to ensure that all personal information is handled in accordance with standard security measures. By using the Services, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information will be transferred outside of Quebec.

We may use [certain technologies](https://corporate.mattel.com/cookies-and-technologies) that allow you to be identified, located, or profiled. You may opt out by going to the [_Mattel Privacy Choice Portal_](https://submit-irm.trustarc.com/services/validation/3773efbf-1df1-4e6a-8d00-010aec40f536).

We will only use your personal information for the purposes stated at the point of collection or as otherwise noted in this Privacy Statement. Subject to applicable law, if you are a Quebec resident and would like to submit a request to be informed, access, erasure, rectification, or to withdraw or restrict processing, you must submit your request via this [form](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case) or by calling 1-800-524-8697. You may also use this contact to submit any requests for information on our privacy practices or to submit a complaint regarding our practices. Your request or complaint must include your full name, street address, city, province, postal code, and an email address so that we are able to contact you if needed regarding this request.

You may submit a complaint to the Commmision d’accès à l’information du Québec (CAI) by visiting: [https://www.cai.gouv.qc.ca/a-propos/nous-joindre/](https://www.cai.gouv.qc.ca/a-propos/nous-joindre/).

_Vous reconnaissez avoir exigé la rédaction en anglais du présent document ainsi que tous les documents qui s'y rattachent._ You and we confirm that it is our wish that this Privacy Statement, any terms of use, and all other related policies be drawn up in English.

### **Australia Privacy Notice**

If you are a resident of Australia, the following information applies.

**Identity and Contact Information.** If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about Mattel, please reach out via our contact form on our [website](https://service.mattel.com/us/ContactUs.aspx).

**Likely Overseas Disclosure.** Personal Information we collect may be disclosed to overseas recipients that are located in the United States or any other country in which we or our subcontractors maintain facilities. We rely on your consent to facilitate this disclosure in the United States and other jurisdictions, where laws regarding processing of personal information may be less stringent than the Australian Privacy Principles. In certain cases, we may rely on appropriate safeguards such as standard contractual clauses as a basis for overseas disclosure.

**Your Rights to Access and Correct Your Personal Information.** You have the right to access and correct inaccuracies in your personal information in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law. You may request access and corrections of inaccuracies in your personal information we have in our custody or control by contacting us on our [website](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case)[.](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case) The purpose of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to their personal information records.

**Third-party Advertising.** As discussed above, we work with certain third-party advertising companies in connection with our online advertising and those companies may set cookies or other tracking technologies in connection with providing advertising related services to us. Please refer to EDAA’s choice page at [www.youradvertisingchoices.com](http://www.youradvertisingchoices.com/) to learn more about your choices related to advertising with respect to participating EDAA member companies.

**Complaints and Resolving Concerns.** If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice or if you otherwise have a question or complaint about the manner in which we or our service providers treat your personal information, you may contact us on our [website](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case)[.](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case)

You may also obtain further information about your privacy rights from the _Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC)_ at [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/). OAIC has authority to investigate complaints and claims for compensation in appropriate cases.

### **China Privacy Notice**

**中国隐私政策**

**(“China” for the purposes here refers to Mainland China or the People’s Republic of China (“PRC”), and excludes the Special Administrative Regions of Hong Kong and Macao, and Taiwan.)**

**(此处的“中国”是指中国大陆或中华人民共和国（“中国”），不包括香港、澳门特别行政区及台湾）。**

If you are a PRC resident, the following information applies to you in addition to the Global Consumer Privacy Statement (“Statement”).

如果您是一位中国居民，那么除了全球隐私政策（“本政策”）外，您将适用以下信息。

**Definition of Personal Information**

**个人信息的界定**

Personal information refers to all kinds of information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person recorded electronically or otherwise, excluding information that has been anonymized. **Personal information includes names, dates of birth, ID numbers, personal biometric information, correspondence addresses and contact information, places of residence, account information, property information, whereabouts, communication records and content, account passwords, credit information, accommodation information, health and physiological information, and transaction information.**

个人信息是指以电子或其他方式记录的与已识别或可识别的自然人有关的各种信息，不包括已匿名化的信息。**个人信息包括姓名、出生日期、身份证号码、个人生物识别信息、通信地址和联系方式、居住地、账户信息、财产信息、行踪、通信记录和内容、账户密码、信用信息、住宿信息、健康和生理信息以及交易信息**。

Any personal information that, once leaked or illegally used, may easily result in an infringement of the personal dignity of a natural person or damage to personal or property safety, is considered **sensitive personal information**, which includes **biometric information, identification information, religious beliefs, medical health information, financial accounts information, and whereabouts, and the personal information of individuals under the age of fourteen**.

任何一旦泄露或被非法使用，容易导致自然人的个人尊严受到侵犯或人身、财产安全受到损害的个人信息，都属于敏感个人信息，包括**生物识别信息、身份识别信息、宗教信仰、医疗健康、金融账户和行踪轨迹，以及未满十四周岁个人的个人信息**。

**Exemptions for the Collection and Use of Personal Information**

**收集和使用个人信息的豁免**

According to relevant laws, regulations and regulatory rules, we may collect and use your personal information without your authorization or approval in the following circumstances:

根据相关法律法规和监管规定，在以下情况下，我们可能会在未经您授权或批准的情况下收集和使用您的相关个人信息：

a.        The collection and use of your personal information directly relates to national security and defense and other national interests; the collection and use of your personal information directly relates to public security, public health, the public’s right to know, and other major public interests.

与国家安全和国防及其他国家利益直接相关的信息；与公共安全、公共卫生、公众知情权及其他重大公共利益直接相关的信息。

b.        The collection and use of your personal information directly relates to criminal investigations, prosecutions, sentencings, and execution of judgements.

与刑事侦查、起诉、判决和判决执行直接相关的信息。

c.         For the purpose of safeguarding yours or other persons’ life, property, reputation, and other significant legitimate rights and interests, and it is difficult to obtain individual consent.

出于保障您或他人的生命、财产、名誉和其他重大合法权益的目的，且难以征得个人同意。

d.        The personal information collected has been made public by you.

所收集的个人信息已经由您公开。

e.        The personal information has been collected from information disclosed to the public in accordance with the law, including legal news reports, government information, and other channels.

从依法公开的信息中收集的个人信息，包括法制新闻报道、政府信息和其他渠道。

f.          The information is necessary for signing and executing a contract at your request.

根据您的要求签署和执行合同所需的信息。

g.        The information is necessary for maintaining the safe and stable operation of products or services provided, e.g., finding and handling product or service failures.

维护所提供产品或服务的安全稳定运行所需的信息，如发现和处理产品或服务故障。

h.        Other circumstances as stipulated by laws, regulations, and regulatory rules.

法律、法规和监管规则规定的其他情形。

### **Who will Mattel Share Your Personal Information with?**

**Mattel将与谁共享个人数据？**

**Sharing Personal Information with Mattel’ Affiliates and Subsidiaries**

**与我们的关联公司和子公司共享信息**

Our subsidiaries (i.e., the other companies in Mattel) may sometimes need to access your information to provide services to you on our behalf or their own behalf. They need your personal data so we or they can perform the activities listed below, including as examples:

我们的子公司（Mattel的其他公司）有时可能需要访问您的信息，以便代表我们或其自身向您提供服务。他们需要您的个人数据，以便我们或他们能够执行下面列出的活动，例如：

a.        Delivering products and services you have requested.

提供您所要求的产品和服务。

b.        Contacting you about your account or transactions.

就您的账户或交易与您联系。

c.         Sending you information about our sites, applications, and policies.

向您发送有关我们网站、应用程序和政策的信息。

d.        Sending you direct marketing messages.

向您发送直接营销信息。

e.        Sending you product catalogues and other printed marketing materials.

向您发送产品目录和其他营销印刷材料。

f.          Performing internal research, analytics, and reporting.

内部研究、分析和报告。

g.        Identifying, reviewing, and stopping any activities that could breach our policies or break the law.

识别、审查并阻止任何可能违反我们的政策或触犯法律的活动。

**Sharing Your Information with Other Companies**

**与其他公司共享信息**

Please find below our category list of trusted third parties that we may share your information with. We process personal data with third parties/vendors in the following categories:

请在此处查看我们可能与之共享您的信息的可信第三方类别列表。 我们与以下类别的第三方/供应商处理个人数据：

a.        IT Service providers. We use a series of trusted partners worldwide to provide us with IT services and system administration services for both our customer and partner facing activities as well as our internal IT and administration systems.

IT服务提供商。 我们在全球范围内使用一系列值得信赖的合作伙伴为我们提供IT服务和系统管理服务——既包括面向客户和合作伙伴的活动，也包括我们的内部IT和管理系统。

b.        Global payment provider and processing partners. These partners help us to secure a safe and efficient payment process both online, in our stores, and through invoicing or money transfers.

全球支付提供商和处理合作伙伴。这些合作伙伴帮助我们在网上、店内或通过发票或汇款实现安全高效的支付流程。

c.         Cloud storage partners. We store our data and your data in secure data centers.

云存储合作伙伴。 我们在安全的数据中心存储我们和您的数据。

d.        Warehousing, packing, shipping, and delivery partners. These partners help us get our products into the hands of our customers.

仓储、包装、运输和配送合作伙伴。这些合作伙伴帮助我们将产品送到客户手中。

e.        Catalogue printing, mailing, and postal partners. These partners help us make sure our catalogues, magazines, and other printed marketing materials come your way.

目录印刷、邮寄和邮政合作伙伴。这些合作伙伴可帮助我们确保产品目录、杂志或其他营销印刷材料能送达您的手中。

f.          Marketing and advertising partners. These partners help us provide tailored advertisements, promotions, sweepstakes, contests, and campaigns when you are interacting with Mattel on online platforms, on social media, instore, or otherwise.

营销和广告合作伙伴。这些合作伙伴帮助我们在您通过在线平台、社交媒体、店内或其他方式与Mattel互动时提供量身定制的广告、促销、抽奖、竞赛和活动。

g.        Social media partners and online search platforms. These partners allow you to interact with Mattel on the platforms where you are, and allow us to provide tailored marketing of our products as well as provide us with a broader understanding of how our shoppers and consumers interact with us via these platforms and partners.

社交媒体合作伙伴和在线搜索平台。这些让您可以在您所在的平台上与Mattel互动，让我们可以提供量身定制的产品营销，并让我们更广泛地了解购物者和消费者如何通过这些平台和合作伙伴与我们互动。

h.        Survey, questionnaire, and product review suppliers. These partners help us get your all-important feedback about your Mattel experience.

调查、问卷和产品评论提供者。这些有助于我们获得您对Mattel体验的重要反馈。

i.          Professional advisers, including lawyers, auditors, and insurers globally. These partners provide consultancy, legal, insurance, and accounting services to Mattel.

专业顾问。包括全球范围内的律师、审计师和保险公司。他们为Mattel提供咨询、法律、保险和会计服务。

**Other Uses and Disclosures**

**其他用途和披露**

 We will also use and disclose personal data as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) to comply with applicable laws (which may include laws outside of the country you live in); (b) to respond to requests from public and government authorities (which may include authorities outside of the country you live in); (c) to cooperate with law enforcement; (d) to protect our rights, privacy, safety, or property, and that of our affiliates, you, or others.

我们还将在我们认为必要或适当的情况下使用和披露个人数据：(a) 遵守适用法律（可能包括您所在国家以外的法律）；(b) 回应公共和政府机构（可能包括您所在国家以外的机构）的请求；(c) 配合执法；(d) 保护我们以及我们的关联公司、您或他人的权利、隐私、安全或财产。

In addition, we will use, disclose, or transfer personal data to a third-party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, or transfer.

此外，在任何重组、合并、出售、合资、转让的情况下，我们将使用、披露或转让个人数据给第三方。

**Cross-border Transfer of Personal Information**

**个人信息的跨境传输**

In order to provide and improve our services, we may share, transfer, or store your personal data outside of Mainland China if we are satisfied that adequate levels of protection are in place to protect the integrity and security of your personal data or adequate security measures have been adopted in compliance with legal requirements. For example, we may sign agreements with the recipients of your personal data. In any case, we will ensure that the entity that receives your personal data properly handles your personal data and your personal data gets the same level of protection that it obtained in Mainland China. In addition, we will strictly comply with PRC laws and regulations on data security and personal information protection. 

为了提供和改进我们的服务，我们可能会在中国大陆以外共享、传输或存储您的个人数据，前提是我们确信已采取了足够的保护措施来保护您个人数据的完整性和安全性，或已采取了符合法律要求的足够的安全措施。例如，我们可能会与您个人数据的接收方签署协议。在任何情况下，我们都将确保接收您个人数据的实体妥善处理您的个人数据，并确保您的个人数据获得与在中国大陆获得的同等水平的保护。此外，我们将严格遵守中国有关数据安全和个人信息保护的法律法规。

**Your Data Protection Rights**

**您的数据保护权利**

You have the following rights:

您享有以下权利

a.        To request access to your personal data. You have the right to access the personal data we are keeping about you. In many cases, this information is already available to you in your online services from us. Your right to access this data may, however, be restricted by legislation, protection of other persons’ privacy, and consideration for Mattel’s business practices, business secrets and internal assessments.

要求查阅您的个人资料。您有权访问我们保存的您的个人数据。在许多情况下，这些信息已经存在于我们为您提供的在线服务中。但是，您的访问权可能会受到法律、他人隐私保护以及Mattel商业惯例、商业秘密和内部评估等因素的限制。

b.        To request corrections of incorrect or incomplete data. If the data we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, you are entitled to have the data corrected, as long as such corrections are compliant with any restrictions imposed by law.

要求更正不正确或不完整的数据。如果我们掌握的与您有关的数据不正确或不完整，您有权要求更正数据，但须遵守法律规定的限制条件。

c.         You have the right to change the scope of your consent.

您有权更改同意范围。

d.        You have the right to refuse to be contacted for direct marketing purposes.

您有权拒绝接受以直接营销为目的的联系。

e.        To request erasure. You have the right to request the deletion of your data under the following circumstances except where the period of retention stipulated by laws and administrative regulations has not yet expired; the deletion of personal information is technically difficult to implement; or where the processing of personal information is necessary for us to provide our products and/or services to you:

除法律、行政法规规定的保存期限未届满、删除个人信息从技术上难以实现或者处理个人信息对我们向您提供产品及/或服务是必要的以外，在以下情况下，您有权要求删除您的数据：

•          When our processing of your personal information violates the law.

当我们对个人信息的处理违反法律时；

•          When we collect or use your personal information without your consent.

当我们在未经您同意的情况下收集或使用您的个人信息时；

•          When the purpose of processing your personal information has been achieved, cannot be achieved, or the processing is no longer necessary (e.g., when you no longer use our products or services).

当处理您个人信息的目的已经实现、无法实现或处理不再必要时（例如，当您不再使用我们的产品或服务）；

•          When we no longer provide you with any products or services; or

当我们不再向您提供任何产品或服务时；或

•          When you have withdrawn your authorization and consent to our processing of your personal information.

当您撤回对我们处理您个人信息的授权和同意时。

f.         Other rights stipulated by current laws and regulations.

现行法律法规规定的其他权利。

**Information Security Protection**

**信息安全保护**

Mattel strives to guarantee its users’ information security, so as to avoid information loss, improper use, and unauthorized access or disclosure of its users’ data.

Mattel努力为用户的信息安全提供保障，以避免信息丢失、不当使用、未经授权的访问或披露。

Mattel will take various security protection measures to ensure information security within a reasonable security level. For example, Mattel will protect your personal information by using encryption techniques (e.g., SSL), anonymous processing, and other means.

Mattel将采取各种安全保护措施，在合理的安全级别内确保信息安全。例如，Mattel将通过加密技术（如SSL）、匿名处理及其他方式保护您的个人信息。

Mattel will establish special management rules, processes, and organizations to safeguard information security. For example, Mattel will strictly restrict the scope of persons who have access to your information and require them to observe confidentiality obligations. If security events, including personal information leakages, occur, Mattel will initiate an emergency plan to mitigate such events and inform you by notice, announcement, or other means.

Mattel将建立专门的管理规则、流程和组织来保护信息安全。例如，Mattel将严格限制接触信息的人员范围，并要求他们遵守保密义务。 如果发生包括个人信息泄露在内的安全事件，Mattel将启动应急预案，防止事件恶化，并通过通知、公告等方式告知您。

**Information Storage**

**信息存储**

We will properly store your personal information according to relevant laws, regulations, and regulatory rules of China and other countries and regions where Mattel operates.

我们将根据中国及Mattel运营所在国家（地区）的相关法律法规和监管规定妥善保存您的个人信息。

Generally, Mattel only keeps your personal information for a period necessary for realizing our services. If our products or services are discontinued, we will delete your personal information or anonymize it within a reasonable time limit according to relevant laws and regulations.

一般情况下，Mattel 仅在实现自身服务所必需的期限内保存您的个人信息。在我们停止产品或服务的情况下，我们将根据相关法律法规在合理期限内删除您的个人信息或使其匿名化。

**Disclosure to the Public**

**向公众披露**

Mattel will not make public the personal information that we collect. If Mattel must disclose such information to the public, Mattel will inform you of the purpose, the type of information to be disclosed, including any sensitive personal information that may be involved, and solicit your explicit consent or authorization.

Mattel不会公开Mattel收集的个人信息。如果Mattel必须向公众披露，Mattel将告知您披露的目的、披露的信息类型以及可能涉及的敏感信息，并征求您的明确同意或授权。

**Protection of Personal Information of Minors**

**保护未成年人的个人信息**

If you are a child under the age of 18, please ask your parent or guardian to read the Statement and this China Privacy Notice carefully, and not use our services or provide information to us until you obtain the consent of your parent or guardian. We will only use and disclose the personal information of a minor, which we collect with the consent of their parent or guardian, as permitted by laws, regulations, and regulatory requirements, upon the unambiguous consent of the parent or guardian, and as necessary to protect the minor. We will protect the confidentiality and security of the personal information of minors in accordance with relevant national laws and regulations. If your parent or guardian does not consent to your use of our services or to your provision of information to us in accordance with the Statement and this China Privacy Notice, please cease to use our services immediately and send a notice to us promptly.

如果您是十八岁以下的未成年人，请要求您的父母或监护人仔细阅读本政策及本中国隐私政策，并在获得父母或监护人同意之前不要使用我们的服务或向我们提供信息。我们只会在法律、法规和监管要求允许的情况下，在父母或监护人明确同意的情况下，以及在保护未成年人的必要情况下，使用和披露经监护人同意收集的未成年人个人信息。我们将根据相关国家法律法规保护未成年人个人信息的保密性和安全性。如果您的父母或监护人不同意您使用我们的服务，或不同意您根据本政策及本中国隐私政策向我们提供信息，请立即停止使用我们的服务，并及时向我们发出通知。

If you are a child under the age of 14, please obtain the consent of your parent or guardian before using our services or providing information to us. We will use your information with the consent of your parent or guardian and in compliance with the provisions of the Statement and this China Privacy Notice regarding personal information of users. We will adhere to the principles of justification, necessity, informed consent, specific purpose, security safeguards and legal use, ensure strict compliance with laws and regulations in the storage, use, and disclosure of such information, and will not retain it for a longer period than is necessary to achieve the purpose of collection and use. Upon expiration of its retention period, we will delete or anonymize your personal information.

如果您是未满 14 周岁的儿童，在使用我们的服务或向我们提供信息之前，请征得您父母或监护人的同意。我们将在征得您的父母或监护人同意的情况下使用您的信息，并遵守本政策及本中国隐私政策中有关用户个人信息的规定。我们将遵循正当性、必要性、知情同意、特定目的、安全保障和合法使用的原则，确保在存储、使用和披露此类信息时严格遵守法律法规，且保留时间不会超过实现收集和使用目的所需的时间。保存期满后，我们将删除或匿名化您的个人信息。

If you are the parent or guardian of a child under any of the age groups mentioned above, please contact us using the contact information provided below if you have any doubts about the processing of the personal information of the child under your care or guardianship.

如果您是上述任何一种年龄阶段的未成年人的父母或监护人，当您对处理您照料或监护下的未成年人的个人信息有任何疑问时，请通过下文提供的联系信息与我们联系。

**How to Contact Us**

**如何联系我们**

If you have any questions about the Statement, this China Privacy Notice or our personal data processing practices, or if you would like to request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties, please contact us by email, telephone, or mail as follows:

如果您对本政策、本中国隐私政策或我们的个人数据处理做法有任何疑问，或者如果您想了解我们向第三方披露个人信息的情况，请通过电子邮件、电话或邮件联系我们，联系方式如下：

Phone: 1- 800-524-8697

电话：1- 800-524-8697

Email: [Mattel Global Consumer Support](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case)

### 电子邮箱：[Mattel Global Consumer Support](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case)

### **Brazil Privacy Notice**

**Brazilian Privacy Legislation**. If you are in Brazil, your personal data will be processed in accordance with the Brazilian General Data Protection Law (Law No. 13.709/2018 - LGPD) and other applicable Brazilian legislation, such as the Brazilian Consumer Defense Code (CDC) and the Brazilian Civil Rights Framework for the Internet.

We just want to let you know that _Mattel do Brasil_ sells its products through commercial partners, therefore, we do not usually process consumers’ personal data during the sale. However, we may have access to personal data in specific after-sales situations, such as when consumers contact us through the customer service channel.

**Sensitive Personal Data**. The LGPD defines sensitive data as any information that could reveal your racial or ethnic origin, religious beliefs, political opinions, trade union membership, or membership in a religious, philosophical, or political organization. It also includes data about your health or sex life, genetic, or biometric data.

We know that processing sensitive personal data in an unfair way could lead to discrimination, so we take extra care with it.

**Underage Data Subjects**. Underage data subjects have greater protection under the LGPD. In Brazil, both children and adolescents are considered minors, children being individuals under 12 years of age, and adolescents between 12 and under 18 years of age.

We are committed to protecting the personal data of minors. That's why we always process it in accordance with the guidelines of the [Brazilian National Data Protection Authority (ANPD)](https://www.gov.br/anpd/pt-br) and other authorities. and other authorities.

**Data Protection Rights**. Your rights guaranteed by the LGPD are the following:

* Confirmation of the existence of processing.
* Access to data.
* Correction of incomplete, inaccurate or outdated data.
* Anonymization, blocking or deletion of unnecessary, excessive data or data processed in non-compliance with the LGPD.
* Data portability.
* Deletion of data processed on the basis of consent.
* Information on data sharing.
* Information about the possibility of not providing consent and the consequences of refusal.
* Withdrawal of consent.
* Automated decision review.

Please be aware that not all the above rights may apply in all cases. If this happens, we will let you know why your request cannot be granted.

You may exercise your privacy rights by sending an email to the Data Protection Officer of Mattel do Brasil, IW Advogados, represented by Tiago Camargo, at the following email address: dpo.mattelbrasil@iw.adv.br. We will return with a response to your request within a maximum period of 15. You may also contact the [ANPD](https://www.gov.br/anpd/pt-br)  regarding concerns related to  regarding concerns related to Mattel’s privacy and data protection practices.

**International Transfer**. When we transfer personal data subjected to the LGPD to outside Brazil, we make sure it is done properly. This may include using standard contractual clauses or following other ANPD guidelines on the subject.

**Personal Data Retention**. We will be processing and storing your data for as long as it’s necessary to fulfill the legal, contractual, and business purposes of Mattel This includes the length of your relationship with us, plus any additional time needed to meet any legal, contractual, or business commitments (like internal audits and regulatory requirements regarding information retention).

Mattel is committed to keeping your personal data safe! We implement and update administrative, technical and physical security measures to protect information against unauthorized access, loss, destruction or alteration thereof.

**AVISO DE PRIVACIDADE DO BRASIL**

**Legislação Brasileira sobre Privacidade e Proteção de Dados**

Se estiver no Brasil, seus dados pessoais serão tratados de acordo com a Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados (Lei nº 13.709/2018 - LGPD) e outras legislações brasileiras aplicáveis, como o Código de Defesa do Consumidor brasileiro (CDC) e o Marco Civil da Internet.

Gostaríamos apenas de informá-lo que a Mattel do Brasil vende seus produtos por meio de parceiros comerciais, portanto, não costumamos tratar os dados pessoais dos consumidores durante as vendas. No entanto, podemos ter acesso a dados pessoais em situações específicas de pós-venda, como quando o consumidor entra em contato conosco por meio do canal de atendimento ao cliente.

**Dados Pessoais Sensíveis**

A LGPD define dados sensíveis como qualquer informação que possa revelar sua origem racial ou étnica, crenças religiosas, opiniões políticas, filiação a sindicatos ou a uma organização religiosa, filosófica ou política. Também inclui dados sobre sua saúde ou vida sexual, dados genéticos ou biométricos.

Como sabemos que o tratamento de dados pessoais sensíveis de forma injusta pode levar à discriminação, tomamos cuidado extra com eles.

**Dados Pessoais de Crianças e Adolescentes**

Os titulares de dados menores de 18 anos têm maior proteção nos termos da LGPD. No Brasil, tanto crianças quanto adolescentes são considerados menores de idade, sendo que crianças são indivíduos com menos de 12 anos de idade e adolescentes entre 12 e menos de 18 anos de idade.

Temos o compromisso de proteger os dados pessoais de menores de idade. É por isso que sempre os tratamos de acordo com as diretrizes da Autoridade Nacional de Proteção de Dados [(ANPD)](https://www.gov.br/anpd/pt-br) e de outras autoridades competentes.

**Direitos dos Titulares**

Seus direitos garantidos pela LGPD são os seguintes:

* Confirmação da existência de tratamento.
* Acesso aos dados.
* Correção de dados incompletos, imprecisos ou desatualizados.
* Anonimização, bloqueio ou exclusão de dados desnecessários, excessivos ou tratados em desconformidade com a LGPD.
* Portabilidade de dados.
* Exclusão de dados tratados com base em consentimento.
* Informações sobre compartilhamento de dados.
* Informações sobre a possibilidade de não fornecer consentimento e as consequências da recusa.
* Revogação do consentimento.
* Revisão de decisões automatizadas.

Fique atento ao fato de que nem todos os direitos acima podem se aplicar em todos os casos. Se isso acontecer, nós o informaremos sobre o motivo pelo qual sua solicitação não pode ser atendida.

Você pode exercer seus direitos relativos à privacidade enviando uma mensagem para o Encarregado de Dados da Mattel do Brasil, IW Advogados, representado pelo Tiago Camargo, no seguinte endereço de e-mail: dpo.mattelbrasil@iw.adv.br. Retornaremos com uma resposta à sua solicitação em um prazo máximo de 15 dias. Você também pode entrar em contato com a ANPD a respeito de preocupações relacionadas às práticas de privacidade e proteção de dados da Mattel do Brasil.

**Transferência Internacional**

Quando transferimos dados pessoais sujeitos à LGPD para fora do Brasil, nos certificamos de que isso seja feito corretamente. Isso pode incluir o uso de cláusulas contratuais padrão ou o cumprimento de outras diretrizes da ANPD sobre o assunto.

**Retenção de Dados Pessoais**

Nós trataremos e armazenaremos seus dados pelo tempo que for necessário para cumprir os objetivos legais, contratuais e comerciais da Mattel. Isso inclui a duração de seu relacionamento conosco, além de qualquer tempo adicional necessário para cumprir quaisquer compromissos legais, contratuais ou comerciais (como auditorias internas e requisitos regulatórios relativos à retenção de informações).

A Mattel tem o compromisso de manter seus dados pessoais seguros! Implementamos e atualizamos medidas de segurança administrativas, técnicas e físicas para proteger os dados contra acesso não autorizado, perda, destruição ou alteração dos mesmos.

### **Contact Us**

You may direct any questions about the Statement by contacting:

**Mattel, Inc., Fisher-Price, Inc., Entertainment Limited, and MEGA Brands, Inc.:**

Mattel Consumer Services

636 Girard Avenue

East Aurora, NY 14052

Phone: 800-524-TOYS (800-524-8697)

email: [Mattel Global Consumer Support](https://consumersupport.mattel.com/mattelsupport/s/create-case)

**American Girl Brands, LLC:**

American Girl

P.O. Box 620497

Middleton, WI 53562-0497

Phone: 800-845-0005, Fax: 608-836-0761

email: [service@americangirl.com](mailto:service@americangirl.com) 

###
